<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on nathanyor.io</title>
    <link>https://nathanyor.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on nathanyor.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:07:04 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathanyor.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JSON Fields with Filebeat for Snort</title>
      <link>https://nathanyor.io/posts/2023-06-12-json-fields-elastic/json_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 11:07:04 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanyor.io/posts/2023-06-12-json-fields-elastic/json_fields/</guid>
      <description>Premise There are some scenarios where there are simply no premade ingest pipelines for some log formats, even log formats that one would think have something perfectly simple premade for them. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly easy to tell a tool, such as Snort, to output logs in JSON format and then have filebeat automatically decode those logs using a built in JSON decoder.
This came up for me when I was trying to pull out some meaningful fields from snort with a simple Filebeat and Elastic index setup in my GNS3 lab, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t have access to fancy enterprise things like Elastic Agent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Webfonts</title>
      <link>https://nathanyor.io/posts/2023-03-27-generating-webfonts/generating_webfonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 12:03:36 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanyor.io/posts/2023-03-27-generating-webfonts/generating_webfonts/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Not all fonts are created equal&amp;rdquo;  See the following links for some accompanying code:  NotoSansJP-Webfonts Github Repo Webfont Generator POM Fix 2023 Github Repo   So, as it turns out, fonts don&amp;rsquo;t work the same way everywhere. They are different sizes and different formats for different platforms.
I discovered while created this static site that if I wanted to have a fancy font that supports Japanese characters, like NotoSansJP, I would need to either source the font directly from Google (which would require me to rely on Google&amp;rsquo;s resource never changing), or convert the OS level font to something that is called a &amp;ldquo;Webfont&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World.</title>
      <link>https://nathanyor.io/posts/hello_world/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 18:37:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanyor.io/posts/hello_world/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>How does it all start? I suppose the best &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; post is one that explains some of the effort that went into making this static site and the rationale behind its existence.
Before I decided to build this I had several set criteria for creating a site:
 &amp;ldquo;Simplicity&amp;rdquo; Cheap or free to deploy Highly-customizable Lightweight (as in load times)  ⛬ &amp;ldquo;Simplicity&amp;rdquo; - whatever that means 🤷 In my head, before putting this together, simplicity just meant &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nathanyor.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathanyor.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi. I&amp;rsquo;m Nathan.
It looks like you found my static site! I created this website so that I could share what I&amp;rsquo;m working on with others and hopefully create some useful tutorials in the form of a link that I can hand out. I also kind of just wanted to see what making a static site takes.
I enjoy all sorts of things related to aesthetics and IT.
I like to keep my digital footprint fairly low, so you can see what kind of information I prefer to expose on my work socials, and I can be reached out to there as well:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
